Hey everybody, welcome back to this week
in Stardust. We're doing a VC
roundtable. And you may notice this guy
doesn't usually do the VC roundts. I
know Jason is traveling. He is abroad
this week. He is not here. But I'm not
doing this by myself. That would be
ridiculous. We've got an amazing guest
host stepping in. He is a partner at
Menllo Ventures. Give it up for Dee
Doss, our special moderator of the week.
Dee, thanks so much for being here.
>> Thank you so much for having me, Lon.
This is uh these are quite big shoes to
fill. As you know, I I talk I am not the
world's greatest moderator. Jason Jal
is, but I will try my best to entertain
all the lovely folk on stream here
today.
>> We we certainly appreciate your
expertise uh stepping in as a guest
host. That's going to be amazing. And
we've got an all-star panel for DED's
big week here. First up, Canu Galadi.
She's a partner at Coastal Ventures.
She's led investments in PolyAI, Wabi,
Sarbum, so many others. Canu, thanks so
much for being here.
>> Very excited to be here.
>> Awesome. And we've got Chris Farmer. He
is the founder and CEO of Signal Fire,
Grammarly, and Alchemy, among the
notable investments I see here in my
notes. So, Chris, awesome to have you.
>> Thanks for having me.
>> And finally, we've got Sheil Monat. He's
the co-founder and general partner of
Better Tomorrow Ventures, Seedstage
Firm. They're investing in fintech and
vertical AI startups and a and a
wonderful returning panelist to the
show. One of our favorites, Shiel,
thanks for coming back to the show.
>> Glad to be here. Before we go into our
big stories, I do want to take just a
moment to thank our friends at Plaude.
You may notice I am wearing my Plaude
note pin right now. It helps me keep
track of everything we talk about on the
show. Also, just all the conversations
happening around the office. Anything
that I need to keep in mind, it is
constantly listening in only when I tell
it to. I can turn it off if I don't want
to share what I'm doing. And then it
turns everything into these amazing AI
generated reports and transcripts,
whatever you need. You never have to
like, oh, what was that person saying? I
forgot to do the thing. It's just
recorded. It's saved. It's in your
notes. It's ready to go. So, you
definitely want to check it out at
plaude.ai/twist.
And if you use the code twist, they're
going to give you 10% off of your Plaude
note pin. There was a look at one of
those amazing transcripts. So, thank you
to our friends at Plaude. And now,
finally, we could begin the VC round
table. Dee, where do you want to go
first? I think you know the biggest news
of today and of you know maybe I would
reckon it's maybe the biggest news of of
many decades for me at least is this
unbelievable math result from open AI
you know am I qualified to talk about
math no um however you know there's this
meme that goes around which says hey did
you read the latest Ryman hypothesis
result and everyone's like yes I did you
like yes I did you understand any of it
no I did not Did you? No, not really.
And but it's cool and it's a big deal
and and this is what I wanted to talk
to, you know, the chil Chris and Ganu
about is we're looking at these math
results that
let me just start with some some
headline stuff. Seven millennium prizes
price problems exist. One of them was
solved, you know, 20 plus years ago. And
if you look at this result combined with
say the Navier Stokes result that OpenAI
published a while ago um along with some
other researchers you're looking at
major mathematical progress in four of
the seven four of the six remaining
unsolved biggest unsolved problems in
mathematics with AI and there's many
ways we could sort of take this
discussion but you know maybe I'll just
start with with Kanu who's you know at
Kla I an open AI investor like what when
you see results like this what how do
you think about investing in anything or
how do you think about startups and
innovation and what continues to have
value in a year or two years when we're
looking at hey the smartest minds of the
world can't do what AI can do today
>> uh we at Kusa Ventures are very proud
early investors in open AI and I'm very
excited about all the results but as a
as a former scientist
um you know it it does make me uneasy
because it is moving at such a fast
pace. Uh there's a amount of um just the
pace of advancements in all of these
different sciences is is going to
continue to be mindboggling. I think you
know in the in the past um you know uh
Sam have identified that hey people are
usually not great at thinking how when
things compound and we're already at
that uh at that inflection point where
um AI and AI's capability and
generalization and being able to solve
some of these unseen unopen math
problems is just compounding to your
question is very fair you know from an
investment point of view we often think
about um you know what can we invest in
where the ultimate value is not just
flowing into the the token generators
today. what is the next capability that
we can invest in and I can talk about
some of the things that I have been
investing in which I feel could be
interesting but it is a very fair
question um the you know for example
even within related to the math area
right so math happens to be a domain
that is very formal and for AI to
continue to build proofs on top of
proofs is you can see why it's working
um there are domains which are very
uniformal which are you know connected
written in very natural language with
the intent hopefully captured well but
it is not 100% correct and so some of
the companies I've been investing in um
are trying to take real world very
complex domains and formalize it such
that you can do this advanced math and
so the we you always think about what
are we investing in and will it continue
to get better because of the underlying
models getting better and all of the
capabilities that they're producing um
so you know PMAN labs would be one of
them that is going after taxes. Uh Logos
research out of Imperial College in
London is another one that's going after
financial code. But the intent of the
math or intent of the code uh that once
it's captured in a formal domain can go
move much much faster. But and I see I
think similarly in chemistry and physics
uh just in the software or digital land
will move a lot faster and now we're
seeing a lot more companies trying to
close the loop with real world
experiments with wet lab experiments
with robotic experiments and we're
seeing more of that. But it is a very
very fair question about what can we
invest in early stage that will not
ultimately flow into the token
generators and it is harder and getting
harder and harder for all of us.
>> Phil Chris where would you agree
disagree continue that or say hey here
are some areas that I look at or I think
are still valuable or you know it's a
free-for-all. Who knows what we're all
doing and we'll see. Um where what's
what's the take?
>> We spent a lot of time as in healthcare,
right? I think there's going to be just
unbelievable breakthroughs in that
ecosystem of understanding a lot of, you
know, parts of of the human body and and
and life that that we still don't
understand well today like the brain and
complex systems and cancers and all
these types of things. And I think as as
to to Connor's point as you know it's
it's hard to anticipate like how how
powerful this gets as they compound. But
as you see a convergence of all the
different investments that have been
made across life sciences wet labs that
can test experiments really quickly um
and and run through it you know
capturing all of the data that you
wouldn't have historically kept in a
human context because you only put
something into clinical trials if it's
been successful. Whereas in an AI world,
you want to capture all the failures as
well um in order to to to train and
learn from that those data sets. So
there's a lot on the data capture and
reinforcement learning and what on all
these categories and as these things
converge where we get better at
understanding complex systems but at the
same time get better at understanding
biology or or or chemistry or all these
things as the as these different types
of models converge and can collaborate
the breakthroughs that I think we're
going to be able to have is going to be
super powerful and I think a lot of what
I'm most excited about is a potential
impact on human health right um and then
also planetary health and other super
complex systems that you know there's a
lot of debate on what what's real and
what is climate change and all this type
of stuff and it's because there's so
many you know inputs into these systems
that it's hard to sort of really
understand uh the the butterfly effect
of of different things and so now I
think as we get better these models get
better and can collaborate across
different disciplines there's going to
be a lot of exciting I think
breakthroughs and better understanding
um of the ramifications of some of the
choices we're making in these domains.
>> Yeah, I completely agree. I I feel like
it's actually the Matt stuff um is
obviously the first um the first uh
results we're seeing, but that's just
because it's the place where it's easy
to verify that the AI discovered
something actually new. Um but I think
what's very exciting is just
extrapolating that to all of science and
making invention itself cheaper. Um, and
I think like Ganu and Chris said, I
think there's gonna be a lot of
implications in in in other sciences.
Um, I think, you know, cancer therapies,
stuff like that. But I I think the
implication is that AI can create a
cancer therapy quickly. But I think
there's still a lot in proving that it
works safely in humans. And I think
that's where we've done some investing.
Um I think similarly in chemistry you
know you can design a better battery
chemistry but um someone still has to
manufacture that battery battery and
test the battery and I think that's why
you're seeing so much in physical AI.
ODU is the all-in-one management
software that brings everything you need
into one easy to use platform and
founders know it's going to save them a
lot of their time and time is money time
is valuable. That's all you have as a
founder. Let's take a moment and we're
going to explore one of these real apps
that you get access to when you sign up
for ODO. Let's check out ODO Studio. ODU
Studio lets you customize or reshape any
of the tools on their platform or even
build your own original productivity app
all without knowing how to code. So, if
your software company needs a
specialized customer pilot and
onboarding tracker, you can easily knock
one out yourself in ODO Studio. Or if
you're constantly lending out laptops,
hardware, or microphones like we do in
our production facility, well, you can
build your own equipment checkout and
asset tracker in just minutes. Why wait
for someone else to invent the software
your company needs? Build it yourself in
ODO Studio. If you're cobbling together
your back office across five different
apps, get started today at odo.com/twist
and your first app is free. That's
odo.comtwist.
>> You know, maybe one thing that I
struggle with and I I agree with all of
you guys, right? Like, so this is this
is true. And there's all these other
domains that are non-verifiable or
domains where, you know, you kind of
have to go the additional last mile that
maybe you don't think a big lab will do.
Um but the thing that I struggle maybe
to be very honest with you the most with
is you look at these big labs and well
compute is clearly very constrained in
the world and it is uh you know it's a
it's a rich person's game. I mean there
are certain companies who are able to
commit billions and billions and dollars
of dollars to compute and their compute
efficiency defined by you know the
revenue they can generate for every
incremental
dollar of compute that they purchase is
is probably the best in in the market
versus any other kind of startup that
tries to compete. So it's almost an
unfair balance of intelligence in many
ways where how could a company possibly
compete with an open AAI or an anthropic
who has you know hundreds and thousands
of thousands of GPUs with you know a
poultry maybe 5,000 10,000 how does one
how do you think about that like is does
that re sit with you or do you still
believe no you don't actually have to
have the most compute to be able to to
do this um how bitter lesson do do you
think you are when it comes to to that
sort of thing?
>> I I I'm not at all a believer that the
models are just going to own everything.
Um, you know, I think that's
intelligence, right? If you isolated
that that that's great and it's
obviously a critical foundational input
and and and incredibly valuable, but how
you apply that intelligence and how you
give it context and permissioning is
going to be critical. Like, you know,
there's a reason why Ford deploys
engineers have become such a thing in
recent years. There's a lot of change
management, a lot of guard rails, a lot
of, you know, trust building that needs
to happen that [clears throat] a lot of
companies are going to have to wrap
this, you know, that the intelligence in
context and permissions in order to
actually do anything agentic, right? And
so the change management piece is
non-trivial. Then there's tons of
proprietary data sets. We do a lot in
vertical AI. We we used to be probably
80% hor you know horizontal SAS and hor
you know with with a heavy ML element
and then we flipped to 80% vertical AI
because I think you can build data
density in lots of different use cases
where the model may have intelligence
but it doesn't have anywhere near the
context that you have because you've
you've built that up it you're you're
going to outperform dramatically and
that can take many shapes like for
example we have a company called Evenup
in the personal injury laws space I mean
they're the dominant player in that
domain because they've seen all the
different cases and back and forth with
negotiations with insurance and 99% of
that data is in the private domain.
you know the the the the big models like
what are they going to do against that
with somebody who has so much dominance
in a vertical or for example a company
like all allhealth which is a clinical
grade wearable right that has all of
your personalized context on your you
know uh bio feedback and whatnot like
that you know the models help unlock
that data but it's that personalized
data for early detection of you know
issues that you may have on heart or or
or whatever
um that that you you need to augment the
intelligence with context on a person or
an industry or whatever it is. And so I
think there's lots of opportunities to
organize and unlock intelligence through
the workflows, context, permission
systems, guard rails, security, all of
the things that need to be wrapped
around it to to actually get that
horsepower to the ground.
>> There are a few different things that
I'd point out. Like I am obviously a
believer in large language models the
way the transformers are built today and
their scaling laws because you know
those have worked and all of the large
labs are going down that path. Um I do
think there is a ton of opportunity to
improve them. We're still in the very
early innings like these models are very
inefficient. The amount of data they
need to train, the amount of compute
they need to train, the amount of
compute they need to serve, they're all
very very inefficient. And there are
tons of very interesting work happening
outside of these labs in solving some of
these problems. Um I think some of the
uh you know opportunity that Chris
mentioned is very true today because
there is limited context that these
models can work because the underlying
compute infrastructure is still very
expensive. um if there were a way to
have very very long context possible.
It's not limited to 1 million tokens as
of today, but maybe 100 million maybe,
you know, maybe the how you surface that
information and what you really need to
retrieve ahead of time, etc. All of that
changes. Um, so I think there'll be a
ton of different algorithmic approaches
that will improve and it might come out
of labs outside of uh you know the the
labs you mentioned. I also think you
know already because of the current lack
of HBM or current lack of resources
there is innovation happening from open
labs uh and it's partly driven because
of the constraints in the current
ecosystem but there is innovation so
there's a ton of innovation that's going
to come out um I also don't believe that
LLMs and transformers will be the only
way for us to get to you know whatever
we consider
AGI or you know SI etc whatever the the
the current uh term for it is uh it's
it's going to be different types of
intelligence, different types of
approaches for artificial intelligence.
Um and so I'm very bullish on like there
will be a ton of opportunity. Um and
then there's this whole other thing
about you know like maybe in specific
areas where you need data collection
from the physical world labs may not
think about it going early but there is
a flywheel to be had um in in in those
areas because you're collecting the
data. uh you know for for example we
have a a a weather modeling company
called windborn that collects institute
data from different points in the
atmosphere um and they will just be
ahead of anybody else collecting those
data points so there is a a physical
world data flywheel opportunities as
well and we've been investing in those
um and and I can go on and on about that
but I think um yeah I I don't believe
that just scaling up will be the only
way for us to continue u winning the
ultimate challenge for the next couple
of years yes and I also believe that the
short the constraints in compute and
other uh components is may not be it's
it's not like five seven years from
today and probably for the next two to
three years. Yes.
>> Yeah. I think at some point compute
stops being the bottleneck in all of
these things like like we talked about
like you can create a bunch of promising
molecules and you know right now
something that costs $50 million to
create you know a few years from now
might be in the thousands of dollars and
it might not be that compute is the
constraint actually it might be lab
capacity the ability to do clinical
trials manufacturing patents all that
kind of stuff might be the constraint so
I I I think right now it certainly feels
feels like the big labs are where this
kind of research gets done, but I don't
I don't know that that's necessarily
needs to be the case in the future.
>> Can we just double click on that real
quick? What do you think, Shield, is
going to change that's going to make are
we just going to be able to make a lot
more chips? Is it going to be the chips
get way more efficient? Is it just we're
going to build a lot more data? What's
going to happen that's going to make
compute become so much more widely
available? Yeah, I think it's all of the
above and sort of like the the frontier
model production is like what we're
relying on today. you it it need not be
that like it may be that today's model
today's model a year from now is going
to be much cheaper and you still may get
output from it that that is relevant
there there's so much to be said about
compute there's another but so when I
look at labs I think of or generally
let's talking about AI there's data
there's compute there's maybe
algorithmic improvements there's a
couple of other things here and there uh
there's this tweet that I saw this
morning that I thought was was was
interesting it's a tweet maybe we can
pull this up uh Gokul says um many of us
may know Gokul already says you know the
the fastest company to go from uh zero
to a billion in revenue run rate is
actually not any of these guys that
you've heard of it is actually a data
company and you know Shio Chris Kanu you
you guys are all seed investors you guys
see seed investments all the time I am
sure that you have seen a 101 different
RL environment ment/data companies that
sell to labs and I'm sure you've also
seen companies that come and say hey you
know we're at hund00 million in in
revenue or you know an enormous amount
of revenue in a very quick amount of
time most of which is typically
nonrecurring
but um how do you how do you assess this
like do you invest in those kinds of
companies I've heard a mix of different
opinions from sort of my investor
friends and and and and and various
different people. Some people are like,
"Look, I don't touch that kind of stuff.
I don't believe it has long-term value."
Some people are like, "Who knows what
has long-term value? If anything, I
think data will always be something that
labs need. So, you know, this is as good
of a bet as any." And then yet others
caveat it by saying, "Yes, and but I
don't know what value I would pay for
these things because they definitely
don't trade like software businesses.
They're non-recurring. um the margins
vary uh to say the least. H how do you
how do you guys assess this? Like would
you guys invest in this kind of stuff?
And if so, what type of data companies
would you invest in? I know a lot of you
out there listening are wanting to start
your own company. So, if it's finally
time for you to make your dream into a
reality, you can't find a better partner
than our pals over at Northwest
Registered Agent. Northwest Registered
Agent is now offering free identity
services. That means a free domain name,
open- source web hosting, a business
email and phone number, and everything
else that's going to make your new
startup look and feel like a
professional company, all with no
purchase required. And this is free done
right. They're not passing your data
along to any third-party vendors, and
they're never going to sell it. So, if
you have an idea you can't get out of
your head, or if you're already building
something amazing, get started with
Northwest for free and upgrade as you
grow. Learn more at
northwestregisteredagent.com/twistdomain.
>> We're we're investors in in companies
like Micro1 um you know that are doing a
lot of training, reinforcement,
learning, that type of thing. Um
you know there there's just there's a
there's just so much capacity to do
that. I think you have to get to the
frontier. You've got to be at the front
lines, understand the nature of this
data, what's working, what's not
working, how to apply it, and then, you
know, great entrepreneurs at the end of
the day is what we're backing to to to
figure this out, right? And to see where
they can, you know, migrate to
corporations to help them um adjust
um and and tweak their data um in order
to apply it in their particular
personalized use case. um you know and I
think it's it's going to move from the
labs to a broader set of end customers
um you know and and so we have a we have
a number of companies doing this in
different verticals and whatnot and yeah
the growth is explosive and it's very
concentrated in a handful of labs today
but all of them have a thesis of how it
will be applied to broader enterprise
because I do think that as you move to
more openweight models you've already
seen a massive migration per the
verscell data that was one of the sort
stunning shifts from proprietary models
to open weight models. It went from like
8020 to 2080 in a matter of months,
right? And as these corporations start
to get more adept at this, build the
skill sets inhouse to personalize, you
know, for their own use cases and build
their own defensibility over time versus
outsource it all to to to proprietary
models. I, you know, I think there's
going to be a lot of need for this
across any large business. And so you
know how they do that bridge there's
huge go to market challenges and
professional services type challenges
but I I think there you know some of
this will be enduring but some of it
will also you know come back down uh
pretty dramatically maybe as as as
rapidly as it went up and so it's going
to be a matter of of u you know how how
adept these entrepreneurs in in building
lock in and and and landing and
expanding just like the SAS days right
with these customers where they find the
pain points and then they keep serving
them and until they become you know more
recurrent and deeply embedded.
>> I disagree with the uh with the
sentiment about data will always be
needed because as we've seen you know
some of these larger model companies
they're good at taking this data and
then at some point they don't need that
data right because a model is just
inherently able to solve those things.
um you know we we don't know the how how
well the openw weight models are
distilling from the top labs right so
the data if the top labs get it the
openweight models also get it so the
enterprises or this existing data is
your currency then you're going to it's
the terminal value seems not exist but I
think Chris's point on at the end of the
day it is the you know the the founder
that they're backing that it's very hard
to argue because I I have seen founders
ers may have started somewhere and the
story started to work and then they were
ahead of anybody else in figuring out
what the labs need next and they're just
ahead and they know how to continue to
build the business and continue to be
one of the most wanted
data or data type or apps build on top
of that data commodity. Uh so I think
the right entrepreneur can still solve
it. We have uh as a fund ventures we've
stayed away from that category which we
believe like the terminal value might
not be there. Uh so for yeah we haven't
invested in anything in the data
category for that reason and you know
but but there are founders that it's
been very hard to be like oh are we not
going to invest in that founder based on
everything we know about them that
that's the hard discussion. So,
>> I think they're super interesting
companies, but I I think like even
thinking about headline revenue is kind
of like the wrong way to think about
these businesses, right? Um, you have to
think about it from a from a gross
profit basis and then even then there
are a lot of questions. We mentioned
customer concentration. We mentioned is
the demand structural or is it
temporary? And I don't have a good
answer for that. I would say like the
models obviously continue continue to
need better post-training data and and
and eval but um
so far it feels like as models have
improved actually the the amount of
expertise actually has has risen um I
don't know if that asmmptotes at some
point um I I think there's a question of
like what is proprietary in any of these
businesses and in many cases there isn't
much but there's a great opportunity
right now to generate cash and they
actually don't require a whole lot of
fixed capital so it's a very interesting
business I haven't invested in any of
them interesting you know I like there's
a couple of threads that all of you
touched on which I thought was
interesting which we you know we talk
about this a lot as as investors which
is ultimately a large part of every
investment we make does boil down to you
know how talented this this founder is
um I sometimes wonder and I've had, you
know, [clears throat] varying thoughts
about this over time, is we live in a
very different era today than maybe 5 to
10 years ago. Um, namely, you know, 5 to
10 years ago, you might have been, I
don't know, 10 years at um a great SAS
company and then you you you you leave
and you say, "Hey, I'm going to start
basically another SAS company. I'm going
to do some top- down enterprise sales.
I'm going to hire a bunch of people." uh
there was there was usually a little bit
less competition and you could be quite
successful sort of running several kinds
of playbooks back in the day. Um a big
constraint for many founders was just
being able to hire software engineers at
scale that actually could build build
out the software. Maybe you disagree
with parts of that. So if you do feel
free to to tell me and that's just a
part of businesses. Obviously many other
great companies in that era existed too.
Whereas today all of a sudden you know
at least when I talk to to young
founders you know the way they work is
just extremely different. I mean the
size of teams versus the kind of
capacity of output that they have you
know it's heaven and hell. You have
teams of five people who are running
thousands of agents in the background
who do a bunch of different things. They
say yes to this no to this. It it sort
of seems like a wholly different skill
set at least when it comes to software.
um you know leaving aside maybe some
healthcare specific or or or fintech
specific stuff where of course I know
you need some some niche uh skill set do
you agree with that and how does that
change how you think of what a good
founder looks like today? Is it
fundamentally the same and you're
looking for the same stuff or are the
skill sets actually changing a little
bit today than it was 10 years ago?
>> Yeah, it's a good question. Um I I think
like the broad skill sets of setting a
vision, selling that vision, recruiting
people are all the same as they ever
were and and that's what it takes. But
um there is this new class of founder
that that didn't exist before. And I I
think that they I would say like in our
experience at least skew younger um and
you have very folks in their early 20s
building amazing businesses, scaling
very quickly um in in categories that
you would have thought um required
expertise um in accounting, legal, stuff
like that. People without backgrounds in
those places are are doing quite well.
Um, but I think at the end of the day,
what have they done? Well, they they
like set a vision for their company.
They recruited people against that
vision and they they sold that vision to
their customers. And so, I think those
things are are evergreen. You've heard
me say it many times now, Bob. If you're
an earlystage startup or small business,
every single new potential customer is
extremely valuable. You can't afford to
have a team that's missing calls. If
your communication is inconsistent, your
customers will notice. That's why
today's episode is brought to you by
Quo. Qo, the smarter way to run your
business communication. I use Quo all
day long. I love it and it's just great
to have that one number that my team and
I can share so that we don't lose any
customers. Quo is the number one top
rated business phone system on G2. And
it's already trusted by more than 90,000
businesses. They're going to bring all
of your calls, texts, and contacts
together in a shared collaborative
space. That means your entire team is
going to use one shared number. So
there's zero chance anyone is going to
fall through the cracks. Money is on the
line. Always say hello with Quo. Try Quo
for free. Plus get 20% off your first 6
months when you go to quo.com/twist.
That's quo.com/twist.
This is one of my favorite products in
the world. It gets my highest
endorsement.
>> I we we take a very biodal
uh view of of how we invest in some of
this. In some areas, you go with super
deep domain experts that understand the
workflows, the politics, the incentives,
the data sets, etc. And they have the
credibility to get the partners they
need to design and build systems to
attack problems in in particular
verticals. But we're also very extensive
investors in what Shield, you know,
described as sort of these young, this
is their first job and they're just sort
of hacker type personas that have no
idea how an industry works. Because we
also believe when you have these
tectonic shifts and nobody knows where
it's going, you need heat-seeking
missiles that um you know are just
insatiably curious moves super quickly
and iterate and it and it's somewhat
Darwinian and that a lot of these things
don't work but when they do work they
reinvent industries to an even greater
degree that anyone from the industry
might do. So like someone from telecom
wasn't going to invent Snapchat or
someone from the hotel industry wasn't
going to invent Airbnb, right? So you
look at it from a completely new
paradigm in a blank sheet of paper. You
have some of the most revolutionary
um you know advancements because you're
not burdened by sort of the the prior
logic and and um maybe constraints that
the industry had faced historically. So
I I I I think it's a really interesting
time for sort sort of young founders um
because you can also do so much with so
little money much like what cloud
computing did for people to sort of not
need all the sort of capex in order to
get off the ground. I mean what you can
do to spin up and iterate quickly with
these AI tools is is pretty incredible
unlock. I think how AI pill the founders
are has an impact on how we think about
them because they're going to take the
bets that they feel will be the right
bets for the company in the coming
years. Uh they're making uh an informed
uh approach about you know what the
underlying capability of the large
frontier models will be and then they're
uh basing the bet on the company on
that. So being AI pill is probably I
guess very very an important axis. Now
um age wise I've seen all various ages.
Yes you know they're the younger
founders but also you know folks who are
like you know clearly like in their 30s
and 40s and 50s. Uh but because they are
able to take the ambitious bets and they
think about you know you know like we
investing in a a chip design company
that is going to release a chip with
like 20 folks because they have so many
more agents that can do a lot of design
and exploration and all of the hard work
of generating the RTL and and also all
the way to physical design. Um I I think
it's just a new world now and so um I
think we all have to reassess what the
what the what the high quality founder
looks like but we're all learning u
there is no uh pre-made template like
okay thou shalt look like this or thou
shalt be at this age I I think we all
have to just fundamentally question our
known beliefs here. Yeah, I mean I my
only thing to add is like for me, you
know, taking the sort of venture hat
off, I just think it's spectacular how
every, you know, generation of
technology seems to exacerbate the skew
of outcomes of every young generation.
So, you know, you know, one way to say
it is it seems like the median gets
slightly worse, but the extremes get in
immensely powerful. And so when I see
some, you know, the other day I was
spending some time with this this
19-year-old. He wasn't a founder or
anything. Uh and he and he just showed
he was just showing me he was introduced
to me by a founder. He said, "Hey, this
guy's really smart. You should chat with
him." And he was showing me his flow of
how he did things. And um and to me it
was just remarkable. He had, you know,
this tab of, hey, here's a bunch of my
50 agents that are running and it's just
trying to break different websites at
once. and then it'll alert me when it
breaks a website and then I get to do
something with it. Um, and I can just
collect bounties off of this. And I'm
like, how are you doing this at at 19?
Just boggles my mind. I wouldn't have
even thought to to to to think about
this. So, it is it is pretty exceptional
how much it can amplify um talent at
that at that level.
Any I do wanted to touch on another
topic which comes up all the time. I was
recently out of my tech bubble and uh I
was at a friend's wedding and the only
AI topic that seemed to come up at this
wedding was how are you using your muse
or instinct? And I thought that was
quite funny because they talked about
nothing else model related. It was just
Muse instinct. And then some of the
hedge fund guys were like, "Our venture
capitalists absolutely bonkers. Why
would you fund this for $10 billion? It
doesn't make money. Please explain this
to me." Um and and so uh let's let's let
me just start with that like
a how do you you know when people ask
you and I'm sure maybe some people have
outside of the tech bubble what is up
with these valuations for something like
an instinct is your is your instinct to
to defend it and say hey you know
actually there's a world where this
might actually be an amazing company for
these these these reasons or are you
sort of like you know I don't I don't
really know um how do What do you guys
think about it?
>> I'm a bear.
>> Oh,
>> I I look I think these personal agents I
think this is actually going to be an
unlock period for personal agents and
it's going to be super exciting in the
next few years. I think a lot of what
I've seen with other people and
certainly applies to myself is there's
only so many points of entry into my
private data that I want and you know
you know it my my Gmail has you know
social security numbers, taxes, like all
sorts of things that you know it just
gets very dangerous at some point to
have too many like things plug into
that. And obviously like Facebook has
just massive distribution. I I was
actually looking this up with a a
founder friend of mine and it's
something like, you know, three and a
half billion people on the platform, you
know, and and and Google with YouTube
and everything is similar, right? I
think it's even greater. It's like four
billion people. It's like half the
people on the planet and it's like
something like 70 75% of people on that
are connected to the internet, right?
And so, you know, the distribution reach
they have, the the intimacy they already
have through Gmail or Apple or, you
know, I think is not is a very very
difficult thing to get over. And so, you
know, I I think either a a more
specialized model versus a gen general
sort of personal assistant. I I just
think it's a it's very non-trivial to
overcome getting people to give you
access to their most intimate uh
information that is dangerous from a
cyber threat type of standpoint. And and
I think people are going to really want
high levels of trust and security. And
and I and I think this is an area that
could favor incumbents unless you're
highly specialized like travel or
something like that where you just have
real advantage in a particular domain.
Um but but we'll see. Um so I think
paying that kind of valuation
even if you have a super slick product
that versus distribution and the ad
networks and everything that the the
huge platforms have I think is it's a
that's a big uphill battle from my
standpoint. So instinct, you don't think
this will overcome distribution. That
makes sense. What about Muse at large?
Like do you think Muse is a billion user
product, billion DAO product?
>> I mean, it could be. I mean, look, I
think it I think OpenAI ran into this
situation, right? They they they're if
you look at what they're building
relative to like I mean, it's Google's
to lose in a lot of ways and they seem
to be footfalling again. they seem to be
on, you know, the the balls of their
feet for a while and now they're now
they seem to be a little off. But, um,
you know, OpenAI, you know, needed to
build monetization, right, to bring the
cost down for a lot of folks. And that's
going to be, you know, some sort of
where the where the consumer is the
product, right? And the and the payer is
someone who has a commercial interest in
selling something to or showing
something to that consumer, right?
Right. So, they had to build out an ad
network. Then they're also trying to
build hardware devices and sort of the
whole stack that like decades of work
have gone in at Apple and Google and and
whatnot. And so, you know, I I think
it's not just distribution. It's
distribution and the and the ad
ecosystem and the wallets and the pay I
mean like all of the different things
that you need in order to do everything
to commercial transactions to
advertising and the network of of of
commercial relationships that you need
in order to monetize this in order to
subsidize it for the consumer to make
these agents, you know, free or or very
low cost for them. And so I think it's
there's there's lots of layers of the
stack that the incumbents have. And
look, startups beat incumbents all the
time, but I don't think, you know, you
know, paying that kind of entry
valuation. To me, the the risks are
significant even if the reward is
significant. And it's hard to justify
that riskreward sort of trade-off in my
mind.
>> I think it was a bit of like tail
wagging the dog. The company had to
raise so much money um because compute
is expensive right now. And um I I think
you you have to believe if you're
investing at that price, you have to
believe that this is going to be at
least one of the major consumer
interfaces. And so
if it if personal agents are a major
consumer interface that we use for
travel purchases, um restaurants, those
are the things people are using them for
right now, insurance, a bunch of others.
Um you can certainly make money. I don't
I don't doubt that you can make money
doing it. Um, I think where I struggle
is that Instinct will be the winner
rather than OpenAI, Google Meta, maybe
Apple. Um, and of course, we've seen
since the time that Instinct came out a
couple months ago, we've seen a whole
host of other agent companies come
along, and obviously not every one of
them will be able to raise the amount of
money you need on compute to be
successful. Um, I feel like Instinct did
a tremendous job at their launch and um,
at least four VCs got a lot of hype
early. They were out a little bit before
Muse and that was great. Um, Muse is a
phenomenal product. Uh, you've seen it
in Meta's stock price. Um, but Instinct,
you know, I I personally use Instinct
all the time. Um, and I've tried out
others. Hark came out yesterday. Uh,
Sesame has a product. There's several
other products that I saw just launching
today. People are constantly messaging
me, hey, try this one. I actually have
personal agent fatigue. Um, where I'm
pretty reluctant to try another one. And
again, input all of my data. So, uh,
it'll be interesting to see what
happens. I personally think that the
large companies have a huge benefit
here. Um, but I can understand why you
would underwrite Instinct to a 10
billion, which is like what are the odds
that this becomes the major consumer
interface? That's worth a lot of money
and if the odds of happening, you know,
you sort of like build some distribution
on what how the likelihood of that
happening. Uh, I think it's tough
though. And then just to follow up, do
you think Muse is going to be that say
say Instinct maybe struggles to compete
on distribution? Do you think Muse
actually hits a billion you know daily
users who continue to use personal
agents or I mean and I asked this
question in the vein of like or you know
is this sort of a first world type
problem of like people have to book
flights and restaurants in the in the
Bay Area but most of the world really
doesn't care that much about this. How
do you where do you stand on that?
>> Yeah, I think a billion users is a big
number. Um, and and I don't think that
there's a billion DAUs for this product,
but there are a lot of use cases out
there. There are a lot of like in a lot
of the world, you still have to like
enter information into a shitty system.
Like I've used it for a lot of medical
things. Um, and actually, interestingly
enough, um, like I I used it to pay a
healthcare bill recently and, um, Muse
wouldn't do it because it only has my
tokenized credit card data. Um, Instinct
stored my credit card data in plain
text, which is not great, but it
actually was able to pay my medical bill
in a way that Muse was not able to. But
I I I think there are certainly hundreds
of millions of DAUs that this is a
product people can use. People talk
about it as if like only VCs have this
problem, and it's true. People don't
travel as much as we do. Um, but people
do make purchases. Um, I over the
weekend was at a bachelor party and um,
I actually used it instead of splitwise.
It actually automatically knew what
purchases I'd made and it was just like
and it had a spreadsheet of everybody
who was there and what times they were
coming in. So, it actually automatically
split everything amongst everyone
instantly. Pretty useful thing. Again,
not something that happens every day,
but happens often enough for everyone. I
>> I think the category can become really,
really large, right? this could become
the way that people interface with
anything digital, right? Like, you know,
if if I just work with my agent, I
happen to be trying out Vajjo, which is
a KV portfolio company, their Asian foe.
Um, if I don't need to call another
physical business to, I don't know,
organize my 8-year-old's birthday party,
I am happy, right? Like all the way, you
know, take is they can go even recruit
the human they would need to go carry
out a task. Um, if somebody else can
just take over all that from my plate, I
think the value I would pay could be
very high. So I I do think that if the
if the company gets the trust gets into
the workflow of our day-to-day lives and
like Shel said, you know, we have the
fatigue like we don't want to continue
to train different agents and get them
connected on how we think about and what
our preferences and how we would like to
do work. So there is stickiness possible
here. So I do think the category can be
very very large. Um I am not a consumer
investor and so coming in at a 10
billion kind of a price would be like
just something I would not think of. So
very early bets on trying out something
very different uh approach. Uh you know
I did make an investment in a company
called Rabbit that got a lot of flack
because they promised too much. But if
you look back like this is what they had
promised like you would have a device
you would just talk to it. It would do
the task that you need and not worry
about individual apps. So the but coming
in at a very early price to say like hey
this is a bet worth taking. I would do
that a 10 billion price as an entry
point. I would be worried about that.
>> I have to go around the table and ask
everybody what their favorite use case
for themselves. I know Sheila, you
already had a great one um for a
personal assistant was because everyone
keeps asking me this and they're like,
"Look, I can only think of flights and
you know these really stupid sort of
basic things I could already click
buttons to do." Uh my personal favorite
one so far has been and I guess it's
it's with an asterisk as it's still yet
to be completely done is I was flying
back from from this wedding from from
the EU and two of my flights back toback
were delayed. So I ended up being 6
hours late and I was just frustrated. I
find out thanks thank you um I'm not
going to say which I use instinct. Okay.
Thank you, Instinct, for telling me that
that I'm eligible for a € 600
um uh refund because this is how the EU
works. So, I said, "Great. I don't I
don't want to fill any forms. Can you go
and figure out how to get me this this
amazing refund cuz my flight's 6 hours
late?" And it went ahead and did a bunch
of stuff and chatted with an agent and
tried to escalate to a real person and
then did that and then asked for their
manager and it was it was just
phenomenal. and they sent a few emails
and it said, "Look, your case, here's
your case number. We're going to get it
for you." Um, I was very impressed. I
said, "Look, if you can automatically
get me that the money that I clearly
rightfully deserve for my flight being
late, um, this is a good use case of of
an agent." So, with that, uh, you know,
Chris Ganu, anything anything exciting
that you have used instinct or muse for?
>> There's a lot of stuff like that. Um,
you know, there's a lot of stuff where
there's like a little bit of friction
and using an agent makes it easier. You
do wonder like so many business models
are built on that little bit of friction
preventing people from doing it. So, you
do wonder what changes. I I do a lot in
fintech and I think a lot about finances
and you know, credit cards, they charge
you more interest. If an agent can
automatically move your debt from a
credit card somewhere else, what
happens? There's a bunch of things like
that. Um so I think that's another
interesting thing is like how do
businesses change when friction is
reduced. Yeah, I haven't used Instinct
um for the reasons I mentioned mostly
because I didn't want to give it access
to you know all of the data. Um, but I
have built personal operating systems
and claude and whatnot that I find sort
of really helpful as like a chief of
staff for big pro big complex projects
that sort of take all the inputs from,
you know, all the different, you know,
whether it's granola or, you know,
calendar and email and all this type of
stuff with with with all the research I
do around a project. On top of it, I'm
I'm also really bullish on personal
finance use cases cuz it's like the bane
of my existence of like got to aggregate
all this stuff and then give it to an
accountant or whatever it is like just
the paperwork health on the health care
side like that type of stuff is the
stuff that not only is it time consuming
and requires some level of expertise and
there's tons of intentional bureaucracy
and friction in that but it's also like
very painful like sort of time on on
things that I don't enjoy doing. Um that
I would, you know, have a lot of value
um for those types of use cases. I'm
most bullish and excited about sort of
personal finance use cases and and just
all the administia that we that we deal
with in our lives that that hopefully we
can identify and not have to deal with
uh insurers that deny things for for
stupid reasons when they really
shouldn't.
>> I haven't used them for any of cases
where I would have to share any personal
information like my credit card or SSN.
I mean, there was an incident yesterday.
somebody reported that uh you know their
agent shared their personal bank account
information on a on a company's group
Slack etc. So I don't trust it but for
you know like I mentioned organizing my
8-year-old's birthday party calling up
different places who can accommodate
with you know these business are open
between 9 and 5. I have other things to
do between 9 and 5 Monday to Friday. I
don't want to be on a phone calling up
who I called, what information I gave
them, what was the next follow-up step,
what's I need to fire up a quote. Like
all of those bloody annoying tasks can
be now taken care of by my foe. I' I'd
pay for that, right? So, um yeah, I've
been using it for very lightweight but
just stuff or areas which are not
exciting for me.
>> Fascinating. Fascinating. I guess one
thing that I I was um thinking about
hypothetically kind of to shield your
point is there was this really viral um
Twitter post that I saw maybe about a
week ago where um it it was some senior
banker I believe who kind of made this
hypothetical which I I kind of thought
was a little bit absurd but he was like
well if everyone's going to use a
personal agent and everyone says hey
help me with my finances then what if we
have a bank run and uh because
everyone's agents tell them, hey, you
ought to take all your money out of the
bank and um put it in XYZ assets. Do you
you know I guess how do people feel? I
mean not specifically about that but
this general highle idea which is the
more that the more diffusion that
happens with these AI tools wi within
humanity more people are going to
outsource their decision making perhaps
to you this homogeneous sort of entity
that makes decisions in you know
surprisingly similar ways across
different groups of people and what are
the implications of that for the systems
that weren't built for this sort of, you
know, mass homogeneous behavior to
happen at once. Um whether it's
something as simple as everyone now
wants to have reservations to the top
hotel, a top restaurant in San Francisco
and so they can't accommodate anything.
Um or whether it's a bank run or whether
it's one of like a hundred different
things that could go wrong because
systems weren't really designed to
handle that sort of behavior. Do you
think that's a real risk? and and what
happens and how do we how do we control
for something like that?
>> I think there's a lot of systems in the
world that are built on breakage, right?
that that the very sophisticated that
can h that are at scale that can hire
people to help them navigate whether
it's you know you fighting the airline
to get you know your $600 back or it's
you know insurance is a very common one
obviously like where they deny things
that they should really do and put hoops
and but there's always been like rebates
all you know all sorts of things that
are you know that make you feel like
you're getting a good deal on something
but then it makes it very painful to
actually execute you and get what you're
you're due. I I think agents will
hopefully reduce some of that friction,
right? And it'll become more transparent
and more rules-based like you know banks
will have to become more competitive on
the interest rates that they pay right
for being your bank account otherwise
you'll move it to somewhere that pays a
higher interest because the friction is
removed for doing that and so I think it
it will it will force some leveling of
the playing field I think in certain
areas and there'll certainly be
companies that try to to fight back
against that but at some point when you
have a relentless agent on your you know
on your side. I I think you know
businesses will have to to clean up some
of those elements. We are not going back
to a world where we don't know this
capability of AI exists or you know the
the fact that an agent can take care of
the things that I don't want to do and
if businesses on their side don't keep
up like they can't accommodate an agent
calling and taking the order etc or like
doing you know the number of orders they
can do or trust issues or you know
mention banks like the the businesses
will have to solve it at their end and
more opportunities for startups to go
solve that um and and think different
like what could be the right way what
could be the long-term um correct way of
having this system work.
>> We're already seeing it in searches,
right? Like how Google search was
designed for humans and you would go
down like one page, two pages and that's
it. Like that was a search. Agents don't
search like that. Agents can go to 800
of those links and try to surface our
best information. U this is you know
high levels company uh parallel systems
is working on cuz we have to rethink how
the world is going to exist. um given
now that we know AI and agents are not
going away. Uh and I think this is going
to be opportunities for businesses to
you know get more AI build and and serve
their customers with matching
capability. There's one there's okay
there's one thing that I can't get away
with this uh this podcast uh not talking
about which is uh man I woke up I think
it was Wednesday last week to the
funniest drama that I have seen on
Twitter in a while and this was factory
vcognition
and I happened to be on a plane with a
bunch of people who happen to be in
venture and we were just smiling to
ourselves going like I'm not sure why
this is such a big deal but I'm glad
glad it happened cuz it's so
entertaining. Um [laughter]
and um and and we we we we happened to
we happened to have you know Ganu
obviously you're at Kosla who was at the
center of uh of of of this spat. I'm not
really sure what the spat really even
was besides, you know, of course there
was a there was somebody like I think on
the board of of factory who who went to
cognition and that's how it started and
then which you know I I mean
I would say this sort of stuff happens
and usually it's a small thing but um it
really really blew up. Uh Matan posted
this tweet. Matan is the CEO and founder
of factory. Uh Scott, the founder of
cognition responded to it and um and
then at some point uh Vinode says you
know factories is a second tier
competitor despite being investors in
factory and I think you know Kanu like
everyone just wanted to know like you
know did Vinod forget that he was an
investor is that was his true opinion
what what happened
>> honestly I know what you guys know right
because it's um I'm I'm not in the
boardrooms of any of those companies. Uh
I I I do like that the MDs in the firm
are going to stand for their founders.
Uh but that's all I get to say about it.
Like that's all I know. Honestly, I I
was not in boardrooms or the
conversations with Chris or any of the
founders. I I'm a huge fan of both Madan
and Scott. So, um yeah, I I know what
you guys know. I think there's a more
there's an interesting question here
around should should investors be
investing in competitive companies and
that you know really for a long time it
wasn't a thing and then in this cycle
it's super accelerated and and most of
the the multi-stage funds have multiple
investments in in competing companies
and I think um what I've seen is people
tend to take favorites and it's the
company that's doing that's doing well.
I think in this case both are doing
fairly well. Um and you have just
different partners defending their
company. Um I I wonder if at some point
founders say, "Hey, this is
Like we're not going to talk to you."
That was the case like 10 years ago and
then it became not the case more
recently. Um but I I wonder if that
changes.
>> Look, I I think a couple things. First
off, it's one of the greatest strengths
of Silicon Valley. Um that but is also a
weakness is that the amount of you know
basically sharing that happens across
the valley founder to founder on like
best practice and what's going on and
it's an incredibly open place from that
standpoint which is wonderful. So tons
of people are are investors in all sorts
of other companies you know in adjacent
domains and all these types of things is
I think really wonderful to pay it
forward. Um the flip side is you also
gain a lot of intelligence and like
where are the lines on you know crossing
something that should be proprietary and
whatnot and where can you use them in
what context and people are going to
disagree and there's obviously going to
be you know two perspectives on that and
sometimes people cross into the
unethical like I'm not saying I I have
no sense of what happened in this
scenario but um you know just it's it's
very inherent that like you know that
when we have this co-opetition as you
know look at Microsoft soft and opening
eye or all these types of things.
they're partners one minute and then
they're enemies and then they're
frenemies and now they're you know you
just have a lot of this dynamic or
Nvidia right is the you know selling to
all the big labs now they're you know
competing on the openweight side just
like you know you know many of the cloud
guys are now competing on the chip side
and so you you've got just sort of this
fierce competition and it's going to
spill out and get ugly at times when
people feel the pressure right and so I
think overall it's generally a net
positive because it drives competition
and innovation and you know acceleration
of this and trans transference of
knowledge across the whole ecosystem. is
what makes Silicon Valley so unique is
that you've got so many people competing
and collaborating and learning from each
other but it has these ramifications and
then there's some big personalities and
you know no you PR I guess is you know
no PR is bad PR I guess I don't know um
we'll see but it's uh certainly a fight
for attention as well in their in the
mix we we we should mention uh Menllo
put some money into factory this week
since since the story broke so was this
was this part of the discussion at all
behind the scenes or is just like you're
talking about the company and the
fundamentals and not what what's going
on on X?
>> No, you know, look, as you know, uh
these decisions are typically like made
before they're announced. So they were
they were two separate um decisions and
um and and you know I think one of the
things it was funny cuz after that was
announced that that we were um you know
invested in factory.
Matan gave us a shout out. Sean gave us
a shout out. I had my cognition friends
text me saying uh hey like do you guys
like do do you guys not like cognition?
And I'm like, "Look, man. I'm firms
invest like I think both of them are
great companies. I don't know why you're
making it seem like I have to pick a
side." Um, like we invested in in one of
them, but you know, I think I think both
of them are are fantastic companies and
I think there's a bunch of room for
both. Uh, it is interesting to be a part
of um, you know, a vocal public spat in
some way, though. So, um,
>> yeah,
>> I I I wasn't involved personally in the
investment, so I I I don't know.
>> Kind of waited in there just at the last
second, so I had to ask. [laughter]
>> Yeah, you I think the the question
about, you know, our are funds investing
in competing companies and is, you know,
how does that work? I don't think we we
at the outset we are trying to find
because we we obviously don't want them
to fight or want to go after the same
talent or the same customer like those
are hard problems but companies pivot
and sometimes these markets are so large
and you know the the starting point and
in the starting uh wedge could be very
different how the companies grow can be
very different especially given how
quickly AI agents the approach and how
enterprises are going to think about
this capabilities changing so rapidly
it'll be silly to say like hey we one
robotic investment and that's it and we
won't make another one or we have like
one investment in agents and we won't
make another one. I mean the world's
going to move really quickly and if you
find interesting wedges uh and yes you
know if if companies do end up going
after similar talent or similar uh
customers then you know what we do at
Coalent is we have a very crisp a very
clear uh Chinese wall between those two
partners that are working with those
companies and none of the information
ever gets shared. Um it's and we take
that very very strictly. Um and you know
it's again we don't start like we want
to invest in five of these companies but
companies pivot very quickly right now
especially when they're trying out
different business models and different
use cases and if it happens that they're
weighing after the same cases they they
don't share information.
>> Shield Chris do you do you uh how do you
feel about that? Would you invest in
competing companies or does has it
happened that you have invested in
companies that happen to pivot to being
competitive and how do you deal with
that?
>> Yeah at the outset we don't. Um we have
had it happen where companies sort of
pivoted into a closer competitive nature
than we had originally planned and you
know there's not much you could do about
it.
>> Yeah. I mean you know especially I mean
you want to go in intentionally doing
that and and I know some firms have like
a mortal enemies list and then like you
know some founders are like everything's
a competitor you know. Yeah. You know if
I'm open AI like everything from like
Apple to Instinct are all competitors
right? you know, and so, you know, I
mean, I and I think you're going to
you're going to follow a lot of the same
trends like we're you you sort of you
sort of find your wedge of entry, but
then the world evolves the way it does
and everyone is reacting to those same
developments in technology or business
models or the landscape or whatever it
is. And so they may converge at some
points, but at the end of the day, most
of these companies do not win and lose
based on another competitor, right? most
of it is execution and team and you know
and and they find different either
geographies or segments or verticals or
whatever they end up going. So they may
compete for a while and then diverge
again and you know obviously sometimes
they're direct competitors but even even
ones that are direct competitors in one
element often you know don't overlap in
others. So, I mean, it's it's you just
have to do your best to to to try to
create Chinese walls when this happens
and, you know, be very transparent with
founders as much as you can to to try to
manage uh those dynamics. But it it is
it's an inevitability regardless of
where you start. You know, everyone's
following the same trend. So, they they
often end up overlapping at some point.
>> And didn't like Grubbot announce today
that they will use underlying model
whichever is the best model for their
use case. Um I think that's you know
just how quickly you know people's
what's important like what is important
for grogbot to win is getting access to
the best model and you know Elon
announced like yeah this could be claude
opus it could be codex immunity
whichever is the best model they would
use that right so um I think that is
it's it's partly in like yes you know
you need to have the best experience for
your customer uh figure out what your
flywheel etc is and and just use the
best stack that you can create for them.
Yeah, another another example with X is
that, you know, they they had the
capacity on the data center side and
they ended up, you know, leasing it a
very large lease to tens of billions of
dollars to Anthropic, right? So, they're
both competing with each other and
supplying each other. I mean, it's just
the nature of these things.
>> I have like a couple of big um things
that I think are are pretty interesting
as well that to talk about that are
somewhat related to this. Um let's let's
maybe talk about like a somewhat easier
one which is we've seen what happened
with with what's happening with bending
spoons and you know there was this mro
acquisition there was the air table
acquisition you know some of the the SAS
darlings from the 2010s are um you know
now not looking as hot as they once
were. Um yet you know like I think you
know some people like to be very
alarmist and say you know maybe maybe
SAS is dead and yes there's some public
market multiple compression on some of
these SAS businesses but at the same
time like Figma continues to deliver
phenomenal numbers um quarter after
quarter there are a bunch of companies
like that that continue to to outperform
in public markets.
That being said, when when we look at
early stage companies as as you may see
and may know, it is really hard to um I
think Hmon from from GC says this a
bunch in in a bunch of his interviews
which is you look at a traditional SAS
business which is a top- down cell and
it has these 322 dynamics where you grow
3x 3x 2x 2x 2x year over year typically
because that is just the physics of the
growth of the business and how how fast
you can hire sales reps and sell and
quota, etc. Um, and those are just not
quick enough compared to how quickly
some of, you know, quote unquote the AI
businesses or any businesses that charge
on um, consumption can grow. So, you
know, what tends to happen is, you know,
even if you have a very solid modern-day
enterprise SAS business, the talent goes
away. The sales people are like, "Hey,
why am I working here? I should be
working somewhere that's going to pay me
way way more." Um, how does that affect
how you view
top-down SAS businesses? Is it a concern
for you at all? Or is it, you know, this
is a storm you have to uh weather and
then it you come out the back of 20 28
and everything's fine again or you know
what is your what is your view? Is this
dead? Is SAS just dead forever? What
what's going to happen? Is it not
venturebackable anymore?
>> Well, I don't think that is is ever
true. All these things go through
cycles. semis was out of favor for a
while. Now it's the new hotness. Like I
mean defense tech would have been like
uninvestable for venture literally by by
LPA at all for h most venture funds and
now you know it's it's a hot domain. So
I I I don't think in absolutes in any of
these things. I mean obviously the SAS
players have been selling sort of
systems of record and workflows and you
know tooling and whatnot and the AI
companies are often going after the
labor on top of it. So it expands the
TAM pretty significantly um because the
spend on on labor tends to be or
magnitude bigger than the spend on on
tech budgets underneath them for worker
productivity and whatnot you know but as
I said it also changes other dimensions
right so you move from hor you know like
the biggest enterprise companies were
always horizontal because a salesforce
could sell to every industry whereas
somebody who was a vertical SAS player
could only sell into that market but
when you flip it in AI high and say all
of a sudden, okay, you're going after
the labor layer, so it's an order of
magnitude bigger some of these. And now
you can build data density and
specialization and whatnot to get to
better outputs quicker in verticals than
you can do horizontally, you know, like
vertically became, you know,
an an area that became much more
investable in AI than it was in the SAS
era. So I think these things all sort of
migrate through and it's it's difficult
to predict over the long horizon. Um but
you know if if SAS enables the upstream
workflows and you can monetize that I
think the historical as you said physics
of the growth rate of SAS change if you
have to stay at the system of record
level and can't move into you know the
intelligence on top of it and the act
agency and execution then then you're
probably more constrained and it just
has to be factored into the price. It
doesn't mean you can't invest in it.
It's just the capital efficiency and the
price that you enter, you know, has to
has to be, you know, uh, adjusted
accordingly.
>> Yeah. I think it's interesting. I mean,
I think like
some of these businesses are literally I
think of as like cigar butt businesses
where like literally probably they're
going to disappear over some amount of
time because what you can do with these
SAS tools is not different than what you
can do with a general tool. And we've
seen that in like 1.0, know you know in
in the AI era actually we saw it with
like the writing tools and obviously
writing was something that so simple
that you don't need a specific tool for
it um I think that's probably true of
some of these SAS businesses too I think
you know it doesn't happen overnight I
think what happens is seatbased pricing
probably shrinks um software creation
gets easier there probably more
competitors you can do a lot more with
the general models the interface gets
disintermediated and then I Think one
that is probably more true now than ever
is like switching costs have gone away.
It's just so easy to switch from one
product to another because AI can do the
switching for you. Agents can do the
migration. So I I think that is a
challenge and you look at a bunch of
these companies like the ones that
Bending Spoons has acquired and they
have to figure out something and like
what they're doing is dramatically
taking out costs and increasing prices.
They're kind of like a private equity
firm in that way and I think they're
doing a good job with it. I don't know
that I would want to be customer of
those products going forward. Um, but
you know, I I think what they're doing
makes sense. At the same time, some of
these companies [clears throat] that are
trading down so poorly actually, you
know, are are delivering great results
and they continue to deliver great
results. But I think part of this is
look, we had a big overhang of COVID era
0% interest rates where like we thought
those multiples made sense and held up
and part of it is just like when that
went away those multiples went away
coupled with the AI disintermediation.
So it's a bunch of things happening at
once that has led to this. I look guys,
I know we're at 70 minutes in and so we
should probably try to wrap up at some
point, but the last sort of set of
questions I'd love to get from you is um
what what is top of mind for for all of
you now? Like what what are you you know
thinking about, worried about, trying to
learn more about um when it comes to
tech and and startups today? And you
know, maybe and while you answer that
like where where are you spending your
time to learn about this kind of stuff?
Is it are you a call people and talk to
them or read stuff online, read reports?
Um I think that's what a lot of people
uh who probably watch this want to know
like where where do we get our
information from? So and and what sort
of questions are you asking? So maybe
I'll go around Robin and you know you
just spoke. So Kanu, why don't why don't
we start with uh start with you not to
put you on the spot.
>> Like I know I mentioned I do early stage
investing in uh normally fairly like
frontier tech, deep tech. So one of the
things that I try to keep up with
everything that's advancing in AI,
right? So um and [clears throat] it's
it's it's tough, right? Like even my
friends at open anthropic tell me like
it's hard to keep up with everything
that's happening in AI. So you know what
shot do I have? But I try right I do
spend a lot of time with universities
with professors with some of their staff
students. Uh to understand you know what
can be demonstrable in the next 2 3
years versus what might still be hype.
Uh and having a sense of that as I make
investment decisions becomes very
important. uh it helps me assess
technical talent from my portfolio. Uh
helps me assess uh you know what's
really novel, what's defensible like so
I do spend a lot of time in
universities. Um I also have been um you
know helping leading some of the
robotics investments at KV. Uh I do land
up spending time with their target
customers right like some factories and
manufacturing plants. Um I want to
understand what is happening on those
end sites like what is the challenge in
scaling deployment what can what needs
to exist what how it can be solved where
is AI helping adoption um and so yeah
like the physical world around us and
you know what's needed to get past the
the known challenges of adoption in
robotics I've been spending a lot of
time in that and one of the things I'm
trying to get smarter about is you know
new rulings by the FCC on you know what
needs what what is require ired for it
to be compliant for robotic sale. uh you
know today it's like 65% of the bomb
needs to be sourced or licensed from US
USfriendly next year is going to be 75
and really what is the intent behind it
and what can companies do and what are
current companies doing u I'm trying to
get smarter about that and talking to a
ton of um companies but also people who
are coming up with these laws like what
is the intent what are we trying to
achieve and what can be done differently
so yeah all of those are areas where I
spend time uh trying to just have um
firsthand knowledge on you know what
what should be investable
>> you know very similar. I mean, I think
you've got to go to the source, right? I
think it's very easy to be in the echo
chamber. So that means the technologists
at one level that are are not just
developing the technology but applying
it, right? It means the you know the
labs and whatnot that are that are that
are working on the frontier. It means
the end customers that are trying to
sort of use it in their work case and
justify an ROI and you know the change
management and all that type of stuff.
and and as Connor said, also the
regulators, right, which is a relatively
new phenomena. I think as you go after
the labor layer, it looks a lot
different than selling it into a CTO.
Um, and there's it's going to be very
political, right? You see it in data
center buildouts, but I think you're
going to see it in spades and in uh and
physical AI. You know, as you start to
have humanoid robots, people are going
to feel it's hard to choke GPT, but you
can definitely throw a beer bottle at a
at a at a robot or or a Whimo. So I I
think that physical incarnation will
will have a very visceral reaction for a
lot of people. And so sort of
understanding consumer psychology, you
know, how enterprise is adopting and I
just try to do a listening tour of
everyone uh all over the world who is
who is trying to apply this stuff to
understand and calibrate you know
particularly as the head of the firm you
know you know all of the people who are
doing deep dives in individual domains
how it fits into a broader context and
dynamic that you're going to do because
it's not just technology that's going to
impact it's the capital markets it's
financing because the because the
capital intensity is so big now, right?
Understanding that side of of Wall
Street and the credit side and things
that, you know, have not historically
been something that really mattered in
venture, but when you've got
multi-billion dollar data center
buildouts for, you know, or chip buys,
like it's it's a it's a different
dynamic and you've got to understand at
lots of altitudes and lots of
horizontal, you know, so it's it's a
it's a multi-dimensional problem that's
only gotten more complex.
>> Yeah. I I think your first question was
like what what's on my mind and it's
really thinking about we're a seed fund
and it's like how how does what does a
seed fund mean in 2026 and when you know
when seed rounds are getting done at
hund00 million plus valuations at times?
Um where do we invest? Are there still
diamonds in the rough to be found or you
know like are we okay investing in
companies where the outcome is you know
a billion dollars or or less than a
billion dollars and so it's like all
things I'm thinking about
um as we think about the future of our
firm um and it feels like as you know up
until now it still feels like we've been
able to find diamonds in the rough and
come in at a reasonable price own enough
of the company that has done really
well. Um, and I wonder if that's even
changed in the last couple of years. Um,
in terms of like you you also asked like
what what do we where do we read? How do
we do research? I think we at times have
had a thesis on a general area. So a few
years ago we did a thesis around
accounting and did some homework. Spoke
to a bunch of execs in the accounting
space. Decided we want to invest there.
where we invested in three companies and
and they've all done quite well. Uh
would do more in that category. Um and
so you know I think we try to just have
a prepared mind going into anything and
the focus area for us in fintech helps
us do that.
>> Makes sense. I I'll just close out by
saying my my answer to the above and
there's a elements of what you know all
of you said and particularly I like
trying to go to the source as much as
possible for a lot of the what I invest
in that source happens to be playing
with products and software and tools and
actually seeing how these things
function where the gaps where are the
holes it helps me do a lot of diligence
cuz man I we see so many claw decks and
it's so easy to say spew jargon um that
a lot of investors sometimes don't
understand and so really understanding
how the technology works for me has been
very critical to be able to cut through
some of that jargon and be like okay
what are you actually building here what
is actually hard to do here um and so I
do spend a lot of time there and then of
course yes universities and professors
um as well probably less with regulators
than than some of you but um yeah the
but look I mean for thank you guys for
uh for coming and uh I think we covered
a lot of ground. Um so I'm really happy
with how how how this podcast went. I
don't think I can take Jal's job quite
yet, but hopefully he uh
>> You did a great job, man.
>> You were right there.
>> I think JCL [snorts] will be proud of
you.
>> I try to channel my inner JCL. Um and
hopefully he watches this and says uh
it's up to his bar. So
>> I'm sure I'm sure he will. Uh yeah. So,
thank you to our whole panel. Kamugali
of Kosla Ventures. Uh Chris Farmer, he
had to step out, but he's the founder
and CEO of Signifier. Of course, Shio
Monat from Better Tomorrow Ventures. And
Dee Doss, our incredible fill-in guest
host from Menllo Ventures. Amazing job.
Couldn't couldn't have done it better
myself. Legitimately, I could not have.
Uh just as a quick before we dip out, we
have lots of open launch roles here in
Austin, in Tokyo, in Saudi Arabia, and
now in Calgary, Alberta. If you want to
find out more about those, go to
careers.launch.co.
Finally, we have a new Substack as part
of our Substack family of newsletters.
This week in VC, it's going to feature
VC roundtables just like the one that
you just watched and other informative
ones like this every week, plus fresh
deals, posts, and more stuff. That's at
this week at this week inv.substack.com.
Again, thanks to our panel, thanks to
our guest host, DD Doss. We will see you
next time on this week at Startups.